Guide to the Cole Porter Papers, 1943-1971
Department of Special Collections
Cole Porter Papers,
1943-1971
Special Collections M0209
Porter, Cole, 1891-1964.
2 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Restricted: letters are restricted until 2006.
Provenance
Gift of Samuel Stark, 1971.
Biographical Note
Composer.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, radio scripts, manuscripts, notes, tapes, reviews of productions, photographs, periodicals, and clippings.
Container List
- Correspondence
- Miscellaneous. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Alba, Duke of (). 1954. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Berlin, Ellin (Mrs. Irving Berlin) (1903 -). 1954. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Blanchette, Paul G. (). 1952. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Canfield, Mary Cass (). 1954. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Cole, Alice ().
  - 1965(2). (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 1966(1). (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 1967(1). (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Cole, James Omar (). Cousin of Cole Porter.
  - 1964(1). (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 1965(9). (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 1966(2). (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 1967(8). (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1968(1). (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1969(5), incl. 1 card. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1970(6). (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1971(1). (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Darling, Eddie (). n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Davis, Brian (). 1954. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- d'Erlanger, Catherine (). n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- deMenocal, Richard (). 1955. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Duff, Juliet (). 1954. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Eells, George ().
  - n.d.(2). (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1965(9). (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 1966(3). (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 1967(1). (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1968(2), incl. 1 card. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1970(2). (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Egan, Tully (). Cole Porter's West Coast Secretary.
  - 1963(2). (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1964(1). (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 1965(3). (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 1966(1). (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 1967(2). (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1968(1). (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Gertzen, S. S. (). 1946(2). (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Green, Abel (1900 -).
  - 1964(1). (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Hall, Benjamin M. (). 1966. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Halliday, Richard (). 1967. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Howard, Jean (). 1954. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Joffroy, William F. (.). 1954. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Kanin, Garson (1912 -).
  - 1949(1). (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1969(1). (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Kaufman, Norma (). 1964. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Kesler, Lew (). Cole Porter's pianist.
  - n.d.(3). (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1961(1). (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1962(1). (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 1967(1). (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1969(2). (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1971(1). (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Knize, Peter A. (). 1954. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Loos, Anita (1893 -). 1954. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Moore, Margaret (). Cole Porter's Secretary.
  - 1946(11), including 1 telegram. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1947(1). (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Musgrove, Stanley (). 1956. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Paul, Weiss, Rifkind, Wharton, and Garrison. 1965. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Porter, Cole (1893 - 1965).
  - n.d.(1). (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1943 - 1945(22), incl. 3 cards, 4 telegrams. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1946(8), incl. 1 telegram. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1947(24), incl. 8 telegrams. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1948(24), incl. 2 telegrams. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1949(28), incl. 1 card, 1 telegram. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1949fan mail. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1950(21), incl. 1 card, 8 telegrams. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1950crank mail. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1950trip to New York. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1951(14), incl. 2 telegrams. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1952(8), incl. 2 telegrams. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1953(17), incl. 4 telegrams. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1954(26), incl. 2 card, 4 telegrams. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1955(9), including 1 card, 1 telegram. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1956 - 1957(14), incl. 1 card, 1 telegram. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1958(4), incl. 1 card. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1959(11). (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1960(8). (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1961(5), incl. 1 card. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1962(8), incl. 1 card. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 1963(7). (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1964(7). (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - [1965](1), excerpt of part of letter, typed by James Cole. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Porter, Linda (18 - 1954). Cole Porter's wife.
  - 1944(1). (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1946(1). (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1948(2). (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1949(2). (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1950(7), incl. 2 telegrams. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1951(6). (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1952(1), card from Linda Porter's dog, Gracie, in Linda Porter's handwriting. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1954(1), telegram. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Rathbun, Lee Colgate (). Mrs. Porter's niece. 1954. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Smith, Madeline P. (). Cole Porter's Secretary.
  - 1948(1). (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1950(5). (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1951(2). (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1953(1). (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1954(1). (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1955(2). (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1956 - 1957(2). (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1958(4), incl. 1 telegram. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1959(6). (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1960(5). (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1961(7). (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1962(7). (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 1963(7). (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1964(13), incl. 2 telegrams. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 1965(10). (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 1966(5). (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 1967(8). (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1968(2). (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1969(2). (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1970(8). (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1971(1). (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Southern California, University Of. Kate and Cole Porter Memorial
  - Fellowship.
  - 1970. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1971. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Stark, Samuel ().
  - 1946(1), telegram. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1948(1). (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1953(1). (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1956 - 1957(2). (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1958(4). (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1959(8). (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1960(4). (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1963(1). (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1964(1). (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 1966(1). (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Sturges, Howard (). 1949. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Sylvain, Faith ().
  - 1964(1). (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 1969(1). (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Sylvain, Hope ().
  - 1964(1). (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 1970(1). (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Sylvain, Laura ().
  - 1954(2). (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1959(1). (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1965(2). (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 1968(1). (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Sylvain, Paul (). Cole Porter's valet.
  - 1951(6). (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1952(2). (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1954(1). (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1955(2). (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1957(1). (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1958(1). (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1959(1). (Box 1, Folder 19)
- MANUSCRIPTS, including:
  - Smith, Madeline, What It's Like To Be Secretary To a Famous Man, 2 pp. carbon typescript, 2 copies.
  - Cole Porter memo re Born To Dance, a film made in 1936., Typescript, 16 pp. dictated notes. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- RADIO SCRIPTS. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- COLE PORTER'S PROGRESS, short by George Eells, xerox of typescript. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Reviews of George Eell's book. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Biography-Discography. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- DOCUMENTS. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- ACCOUNTS. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- NOTES. (Box 2, Folder 16)
- NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS. (2) (Box 3, Folder 1, Folder 2)
- REVIEWS.
  - Let's Face It (1943). (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Mexican Hayride (1944). (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Seven Lively Arts (1944). (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Around the World (1946). (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Night and Day (1946). (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - The Pirate (1948). (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Kiss Me, Kate (1948). (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Out Of This World (1950). (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Can Can (1953). (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Cole Porter Festival (1955) (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Cole Porter's Cookbook., Looseleaf, carbon typescript. (Box 3, Folder 13)
- PERIODICALS. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - American Ballet Theatre. 1940 - 1970.
  - Critics Choice 12/68.
  - Los Angeles, 12/64; 1/65; 2/65.
  - Parke Bernet Auction Catalog of Cole Porter Memorabilia.
  - Playbill, 5/66;11/67.
  - Reader's Digest, 8/66.
  - Saturday Review, 2/22/64.
  - Show Box, 2/65.
  - Time, 1/31/49.
- PHOTOGRAPHS.
  - Album. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Folder. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- TAPES. 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- OVERSIZE: 1
  - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings. (Othertype OS 1)
Books received with Cole Porter Collection but now shelved elsewhere
- Boucicault, Dion L., The Yale University Dramatic Association Acting Version Of London Assurance, New Haven, 1910.annotated.
  Felton Collection
- Calahan, Harold Augustin, Geography For Grown-Ups, New York, Harper, 1946.Inscribed For Judy From Pep
  Rare Book Collection
- Crosby, Caresse, The Passionate Years, New York, Dial, 1953.Cole Porter letter, 9/1/53 in front. [Letter is in the collection]
  Felton
- Harriman, Margaret Chase, Take Them Up Tenderly, New York, Knopf, 1945.not inscribed.
  Stacks?
- Hubler, Richard G., (as told to), The Cole Porter Story, New York, World, 1965.not inscribed.
- Lawrence, Gertrude, A Star Danced, Garden City, Doubleday, 1945.Inscribed Aug. 24, 1945/ Dear Kitty/ I hope you enjoy this./ Sincerely/ Cole Porter
- Vertes, It's All Mental, New York, Tudor, 1948.Inscribed by Vertes, and Paul Louis ---. inscribed to Cole Porter
  Art Library